

# **Curriculum Vitae for Vinzenz Gregor Eck**

#### Personal information

Address: Hubertusstr. 83 E-mail: vinzenz.eck@expertanalytics.de

82131 Gauting Phone: +49/162/7935345

Born: 21.09.1987

### **Summary**

I am a curious, pragmatic and creative problem solver.

In 2020, I founded Expert Analytics GmbH in Munich together with Ola Skavhaug and Åsmund Ødergård. My educational background is in mechanical engineering where I hold a PhD in biomechanical engineering.

I have 12 years experience in software engineering. My past assignments were centered around these areas: on-edge computation, backend systems for data analysis and predictive maintenance, asset/domain models, data-driven analysis, 2d/3d visualisations, stochastic and physics based simulators and numerical solvers.

#### **Technical skills**

Frameworks NumPy, SciPy, Statsmodel, HDBSCAN, Scikit-learn, Chaospy, Flask,

REST, Sphinx, DOT, GraphViz, Matplotlib, Bokeh, GTK, VTK, OSG,

OpenGl

Languages Python, C, C++, Matlab, LaTeX, HTML, XML, Json, Yaml

Tools Git, Subversion, Linux, Eclipse, PyCharm, VirtualBox, Inkscape, Ama-

zon AWS, Microsoft Azure

#### **Education**

2016 Ph.D. in Biomechanics from the Institute of Structural Engineering,

Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Trondheim. Title of dissertation: "Uncertainty quantification and sensitivity analysis for

cardiovascular applications".

2013 Diplom Engineer in mechanical engineering, Technische Universität

München, Germany.

2012 Master of Science in Technology, Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Trondheim, Norway. Conducted within the Double Degree Program T.I.M.E. (Top Industrial Manager for Europe). Title of thesis: "Arterial Flow and Pulse Wave Propagation in one dimensional Arterial Networks with Statistically Distributed Model Parameters".

## **Professional experience**

2020 –	Founder and Managing Director of Expert Analytics Gmbh, Munich
2016 – 2020	Consultant at Expert Analytics AS, Oslo
2012 – 2013	Ph.D. student at the Department of Structural Engineering, NTNU, Trondheim.
2013 – 2012	20% Department Engineer at the Department of Circulation and Medical Imaging, Faculty of medicine, NTNU, Trondheim. Development of a hemodynamic-simulation tool for one-dimensional arterial networks.
2012 – 2012	Teaching Assistant at the Department of Energy and Process Engineering, NTNU, Trondheim. Elaboration of fluid mechanic exercise in Matlab for master studies in engineering at NTNU.
2011 – 2012	Assistant Researcher at the Department for Petroleum Engineering and Applied Geophysics, NTNU, Trondheim. Set up and conduction of core-flooding experiments under high pressure, to determine the distribution of Oil, Water and CO2 on a micro scale within a stone sample.
2007 – 2010	Assistant Researcher at the iwb – Institute for Machine Tools and Industrial Management, TUM, Munich. Programming a simulation software of material flow based on physical laws for the virtual commissioning of production systems.

# Languages

English Fluent French Basic

German Mother tongue

Norwegian Fluent

### Personal skills

Communications I am proficient in presenting difficult contents understandably and

tailored to the target audience.

Management I am experienced in leading groups and managing projects.

### Some interests and hobbies

Music Guitar, Bass, Clarinet, Percussion, Music production (recording,

mixing and mastering)

Physical Hiking, Bouldering, Dancing

### **Extended descriptions of selected projects**

Activity Edge Audio Analytics - MVP

Role Developer Staffing 8 developer

Description We in Expert Analytics joined forces with Statkraft to evaluate in

an R&D project the usefulness of audio surveillance to measure the health state of heavy machinery in particular hydro power generators. We developed an MVP for an audio analysis system with Siemens industry computers. We installed the edge system at a power plant to record the acoustic emissions of 3 generators and 2 transformers with 8 microphones. The high frequent audio data (48k samples/s) is analysed on side with machine learning models. An edge backend system facilitates data acquisition, data saving, model scheduling, result transfer to the cloud, edge fleet management and code/model deployment to the edge. I was in charge of the backend architecture and design, as well as the audio hardware selection. In addition, I implemented most of the data acquisition, and the edge compute engine which executes the machine learning models. After running for 2 months we already detected 2 concerning malfunctions in different

equipment. The project is ongoing until 2022. Python, NumPy, Yaml, Docker, Aws, ALSA

Activity Arundo - Domain Modelling

Role Developer Staffing 4 - 8 developer

Tools

Description In Arundo, I supported the development of the domain model for

a data processing engine for predictive maintenance simulations. In addition, I was part of a small team to design and implement the core of a standardized domain modelling language framework which could be applied to many projects. The framework would allow modeling physical domains of customer's assets and track changes over time.

Tools Python, NumPy, Yaml, Json, networkX, DOT, GraphViz

Activity Statkraft - Predictive Maintenance for Hydropower

Role Main developer and architect

Staffing 2 developer

Description For Statkraft I developed the backend system for predictive maintean-

ce in hydro power. The backend system includes a versioned domain model, infrastructure to define, test, run and deploy machine learning models, data management and visualisation. In addition, I helped with the data analysis and implementation of the first predictive mainte-

nance model.

Tools Python, Bokeh, NumPy, Json, REST, Azure

Activity Statkraft - Machine learning platform

Role Main developer and architect

expertanalytics.no

Staffing 2 developer

Description Statkraft wanted a common platform to scale and facilitate machine

learning projects from the explorative phase to production. We designed and implemented a flexible and scalable solution that allows for the integration of all common machine learning libraries into one framework. With our framework machine learning workflows can be defined, run and shared among teams. The unique feature is that its fast and lightweight backend is optimized to run ml-workflows in production on Statkraft's systems. This enables a fast transition from

prototypes to validated and tested production code.

Tools Python, Yaml, Json, HDBSCAN, scicit-learn, keras, tensorflow

Activity Root cause analysis in Windturbines

Role Main analyst Staffing 2 analysts

Description Random failing equipment in windturbines lead to losses in the magni-

tude of millions for our customer. With the analysis of weather and production data we determined the root cause and could suggest actions to save the remaining equipment and keep the production up. With a lifetime predictor we could estimate the remaining lifetime of each turbine individually. Due to the data driven mitigation action we proposed equipment was saved, and the losses considerably limited.

Tools Python, NumPy, Statsmodel, ANOVA, ARIMA, Pandas

Activity Statkraft - Longterm Power Management - Visualization

Role Main developer and architect

Staffing 1 developer

Description In Statkraft, Longterm Power Management is based on numerical si-

mulations of complex water way systems, including reservoirs, power stations, and pumps. For the analysis and usage of these simulation results, visualization tools are needed. The goal was to visualize all data in a convenient and accessible manner via web services based on Bokeh. The projekt resulted in a dashboard suite which enables fast and intuitively creation of web dashboards. Statkaft published the suite as Open Source Software among it's Shyft application. The dashboard suite has an integrated time series viewer to visualized large amount of high frequent data in a fast and effective manner. Also, graph visualization tools are included, which are for example used to auto-generate and visualize the topology of arbitrary water way systems at run time. The visualization tool is now used by several projects

in Statkraft.

Tools Python, DOT, GraphViz, Bokeh, NumPy, XML, Yaml, Json

Activity The Planck Legacy Archive Added Value Interface (European Space

Agency)

Role Profiling of the system performance

Staffing 5 developers

Description The Planck Legacy Archive is a website aimed at giving the general

public the opportunity to access and use data from the ESA Planck satellite. In 2015 ESA started work on implementing an Added Value Interface to this website, which aims to allow users to manipulate and analyse data online before downloading, using various data cleaning and analysis techniques. My role in this project was to profile the memory usage of all analysis and map manipulation algorithms. The analysis results helded to determine the optimal size and type of the asynchronous workers spawned on all virtual machines. As consequence, the system handles all user requests in the most efficient

way.

Tools Python, Docker, ANOVA

Activity STARFiSh - stochastic arterial flow simulation

Role Main developer and researcher

Staffing 1-2 researchers

Description STARFiSh is an open-source simulation program to simulate blood

flow in arterial networks with stochastic input parameters. The software combines an advanced one-dimensional fluid-structure-interaction code with methods for uncertainty quantification and sensitivity analysis. I wrote the software as part of my Ph.D. thesis.

Tools Python, XML, Sphinx, NumPy, SciPy, GTK, OpenGl, ChaosPy, DOT

Activity ve3 - virtual commissioning software

Role Developer Staffing 2 developers

Description Realtime simulation software for the virtual commissioning of produc-

tion systems, simulating the material flow based on physical laws. I was working manly with refactoring in addition to adding new features such as fluids based on smoothed-particle hydrodynamics and flexible

machine parts and process goods.

Tools c++, XML, OSG, 3dMax, NVIDIA PhysX, NVIDIA Cuda